Artur Kondas

Contact

Personal Site: akondas.com
Email: work@akondas.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/arturkondas

Profile

As a Lead Software Engineer with over six years of experience, I bring a wealth of skills and experience to any team. I specialize in tech leadership, multicloud and microservice-based architecture, automation, agile methodologies, and mentoring. I have a unique approach to problem-solving, always full of ideas and eager to approach problems unconventionally. However, I am also able to evaluate all options and make informed decisions.

One of my core values is a **willingness to learn and improve**. At the same time, I am passionate about **teaching** and helping others. I have presented at various **tech conferences**, including **GopherCon UK** in London and **ContainerDays** in Hamburg, where I broke down complex technical concepts into easily digestible presentations that engaged and educated audiences of all levels. I enjoy sharing my knowledge and experience with others and am always seeking out new opportunities to contribute to the tech community.

Beyond work, I am committed to giving back by working with non-profit organizations like **Code First Girls** and **Colourintech**. Through my work with these organizations, I help **empower women and underrepresented groups** to break into the tech industry. I am passionate about creating a more **inclusive and diverse** industry and believe that everyone should have the opportunity to pursue a career in tech. I am also heavily involved in the **Open-Source** community, trying to help out as much as I can, whenever I can - I've contributed to projects led by **Microsoft** or **Chef**, to mention a few.

In addition to my experience in software development, I bring a **remote-first** mentality and strong communication skills to my work. Whether collaborating with colleagues or pursuing my diverse interests, I am comfortable working with people from different cultures and time zones. This flexibility has allowed me to develop unique problem-solving skills and make valuable contributions to a range of projects.

Outside of work, I am a **music producer**, guitarist, composer, and songwriter, and I have a passion for exploring new sounds and creating original music. To add on top of that, I wrote the first ever **music video in Golang**. I'm also a break maker and an amateur cook; electronics afficionado; powerlifer and a beginner carperter. All of these experiences interpolate with each other, making me who I am.

Employment

Form3

/ Lead Software Engineer

May 2023 - Present

/ Senior Go Software Engineer

February 2022 - May 2023

- Lead a team that is driving groundbreaking developments in **European-based payments**, leveraging **SEPA** systems to push the boundaries of what is possible.
- Supporting the onboarding of new team members, ensuring that they are equipped with the knowledge and resources they need to thrive in their roles.
- Implementing more robust **metrics** and **logging** systems that enable faster, more efficient resolution of **on-call** tasks and issues.
- Forging a **strong presence** for Form3 within **Go** and other tech communities, driving engagement and sparking **industry-wide** excitement.

BP (via ECS Digital) / Site Reliability Engineer

October 2021 - February 2022

- Developed, from start to finish, a game-changing Observability suite within one of the key products
- Created fully automated monitoring dashboards using Honeycomb and Opentelemetry collectors
- Promoted an SRE Mentality throughout the organization and mentored teams on SRE tenets
- Automating Toil with regards to frequent deployments

Barclays (via ECS Digital) / Go Software Engineer

October 2020 - September 2021

- Won ECS Change Makers Award & received praise from the client for the work on the project.
- Built a set of highly secure Go AWS lambdas utilising Amazon Lex & Connect functionality ensuring high availablity to 9.4 million customers.
- Lead developer and a Key member of a team that scaled up availabiltiy from 0 to up to 70k chat conversations per day in 2 weeks time.
- Fully integrated with **DynamoDB**, leveraging some of the automation provided by the database, configured with **AWS**Secrets Manager, deployed over **AWS** Service Catalog.
- Helped refactoring existing lambdas and services to decrease spending by 40% on AWS.
- Introduced Sonarqube across the Go stack to increase test coverage
- Designed packages to abstract the logic within the lambdas and expose a simple and well documented API.
- Designed the architecture for multiple stacks and maintaned the releases within multiple projects.
- Helped onboarding multiple new joiners and trained them in using Go and AWS services.

ECS Digital / Go Software Engineer

July 2019 - February 2022

- Designed and built a microservices suite for data scrapping and analysis using Go, Python, PostgresDB and graph databases (dGraph, neo4j).
- Services were designed to work in tandem with AI-powered analysis suite.
- Reworked the POC written by a previous team to decrease the time of discovery from 12 hours to 10 minutes.
- Reworked the architecture from previous monolyth solution into a **fully orchestrated microservices suite** with multiple interfaces for various programming languages.
- Utilised the power of Goroutines to make the solution scalable and asynchronous.
- Introduced tiered logging to the service to increase observability.
- Leader of SRE Guild in the company.
- Mentor and upskill a lot of new joiners in the company.

Calipsa / Full Stack Software Engineer

January 2019 - July 2019

- Built and maintained a set of microservices for video data processing and AI integration.
- Using Google Cloud services, NodeJS and custom ffmpeg wrappers.
- Refactored the database queries to increase speed of retrieving the data.
- Improved the **code quality** and **readability** within the whole stack.
- Increased the **test coverage** across the whole stack by **50**%.

/ Scrum Master

March 2019 - July 2019

- Introduced Scrum and Agile workflow and mentality in the company.
- Made first steps in building asynchronous communication mindset across teams.

Sparta Global / Software Development Technical Trainer

August 2018 - January 2019

- Trained three cohorts of students working currently in UK Home Office, Three Mobile or UK Ministry of Justice.
- Taught web development, backend programming using Java, Ruby, Python and C#.
- Mentored and managed students to help them achieve their true potential.
- Recognized by the board for willigness and skill for tacking unexpected challenges.

ABB / Application Specialist

January 2018 - June 2018

- Designed a process & tooling system for **validating web suite** post-deployment. Decreased the time needed **from 4** hours to 5 minutes.
- Application specialist working on globally available web suite presenting ABB tools, systems and parts.
- Managed wordpress, various CMS and SQL databases

/ IT Support Specialist

March 2017 - December 2017

- Harnessing the power of **ServiceNOW**, built a set of data boards visualising the state of service desk, **SLIs and KPIs** across different teams which resulted in massive **decrease of backlog** and **increased the speed of resolution**.
- Member of internal project audit that processed entire applications' move from Poland to India, including knowledge and staff training.

Capgemini / English Customer Service Advisor

August 2016 - February 2017

Skills

Programming Languages Go/Golang, Rust, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, C/C#/C++

Database PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, dGraph, Neo4J, AWS Suite (RDS, DynamoDB)

Infrastructure Terraform, Ansible, Chef

Cloud & Orchestration AWS, GCP, Kubernetes, RDS, EC2, S3, Docker

CI/CD Jenkins, Puppet, GitHub Actions

Version Control Git, GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket

Project/Team Management Agile, Scrum, ITIL

Automatic/Static Deployment tools GitHub Pages, Netlify, Heroku

Certfications

- Gremlin Chaos Engineering Practicioner Gremlin July 2021
- Certified Kubernetes Application Developer The Linux Foundation July 2021
- Site Reliability Engineering Foundation DevOps Institute May 2021
- AWS Certified Database Specialty Amazon March 2021
- Mulesoft Certified Developer Mulesoft January 2021
- AWS Certified Developer Associate Amazon October 2020
- ITIL Foundation Conlea June 2017

Open Source / Volunteer

- Speaker GopherCon UK 2022
 - The Joy of Linters: Good Engineering Practices & Productivity Boosters. Link here
- Speaker GoLab Firenze 2022
 - Call Me Maybe Communication Between Microservices (incl. a technical issue with the projector) Link here
- Speaker ContainerDays Hamburg 2022
 - Call Me Maybe Communication Between Microservices. Link here
 - Cloud Confused Differences Between Cloud Vendors. Link here
- Speaker Devops Playground
 - Delivered a live-streamed workshop on building a ready-to-deploy, CRUD API in Go. Link here.
- Speaker Golang in London
 - Delivered a live-streamed workshop on building small app to play music from the terminal. Link here.
 - Delivered a live-streamed presentation on how to structure small Go programs. Link here.
- Moderator Microsoft
 - Moderated Microsoft Tech Days: Learn Go on Azure event as a Golang SME
- Guest Speaker ColorInTech
 - Delivered two workshops on annual ColorInTech events .
- Contributor Chef
 - Contributed to 5.2.0 #95
- Contributor Grafana Labs
 - Contributed to 7.0.0 beta #22898

- Contributor Rod
 - Contributing to overall functionality of a Chrome Devtools driver in Go.
- Contributor / Translator GitHub
 - Translated Unshaky and Rectangle to Polish.
- Translator Microsoft
 - Contributed to VS Code translation to Polish.
- Technical Trainer Codebar
- Technical Trainer CodeFirst: Girls
 - Delivered two editions of CF:G.

Education

Cracow University of Technology Power Engineering / BEng

2013 - 2017

Engineering thesis: $Acoustic\ measurements\ of\ electrical\ engines$